[Music]
so we've been circling around uh
girard and tantra and whitehead and
i guess i want to know um first of all
what alexander's been thinking about in
the past
little while because you've been
suspiciously silent um
not totally but you mean i'd be right
i'd be less loud than usual so i figured
you must be cooking you must be full of
some bubbling with with ideas so yeah so
i
i haven't been out there in the public
because i've actually been focused on
writing
since i'm writing a book so there you go
uh
working title process and event it's
planned to be the third and
last part of the trilogy with synthesism
and digital libido
of alexander bart and john centerfist
uh trilogy so this is where i'm at i'm
working on the prostate event book and
it's going to be
it's like certain chris and i are going
to release a book after we have turned
60 years old and the plan this time is
to release our sixth book
like you know the tour de force the
magnum opus whatever you want to call it
and put our entire philosophy into one
book
but this is also of course that this is
the story of all stories this is the
meta narrative itself that we're trying
to write
and that's why why the book is called
process and event we're always dealing
with
nomidology which is process over dealing
with eventology which is event
all major stories all major narratives
including all religions
all theologies all philosophies are
either
about process or about event so so does
it work
and and i'm i'm working on um a specific
um concept here called the an object
and and i'd love to discuss this this
concept with you guys because it
actually ties in quite nicely
to what we talked about before and and
it's kind of is it related to your
concept of the abject
is it yes it is but it's the opposite of
the object
it's like it's like nobody's been
looking for it it's uh
we also talked about how could possibly
save christianity or or
turn christianity or reinterpret
christianity afterwards it's a mature
faith to belong to the major faiths of
buddhisms or astralism and
and judaism and i think this could be
key
and i'd love to have your input on it
because it certainly ties into gerard's
work
so i want to start by emphasizing
something i find in heidegger but i
don't necessarily find it in gerard but
i might be wrong
and it's when heidegger is so damn upset
about the german term dasman it exists
in scandinavian languages in the german
it doesn't really exist in english
the positioning is when you say one
rather than you
so one thinks about one says or
one behaves or one admits or whatever
rather than i admit or you admit
whatever
so but there's something very derogatory
about the german
term does man because it's kind of
escaping responsibility it's hiding from
view it's sort of pulling itself
in and this is of course what lynch mobs
do today
so the lynn small people will not
publish their name in public they will
not publish their face in public they
it's the next thing is going to happen
is the lynch mobs will have their own
lynch mobs that go after them by
publishing their names and their
pictures
they don't realize that yet but that's
when it's going to get really messy
right
but when you're in the lynch mob
you assume that all of you in the lens
mob have a shared voice
you you blame somebody else for for
being the leader you you said somebody
else is supposed to be the voice in
there
we all know from objection theory this
of course very girard
this is julia christena it's a lot of
the psychiatrists have talked about that
the police mob is united
through something he hates wrote about
this and did
libido so hitler finds the jew and
unites the germans
by all hating the jew together stalin
found the kulak
and by all hating this independent
ukrainian peasant that he wanted to get
rid of
all the russians and everybody else in
the soviet union could get behind
starting hating the kulak
this is called objection in mao zedong
in china china was hating your parents
the most you know horrible objection you
could ever do it's like all the kids are
going to kill their parents they hate
their own parents that was the culture
of leucine in china
which is of course what we're seeing
today with the lunch mobs so
but but we all know about abject you all
know how the object works
we know that a lynch mob can only get
unified through an object and actually
it's the easiest way in the world
to unify people towards a certain goal
by finding something to hate
together this is central to your right
right
but that assumes that we also have a
voice inside this crowd
that we're all hiding behind so if we
were held responsible
for our view we would blame it on
somebody else he said
no but there's the oneness out there
there's somebody out there the
the the the one is out there we say in
german you was a dust man
you're hiding behind us man in swedish
it's always a reference to some kind of
bourgeois habit
like this is the way we do things but
it's worse than that it's anonymous
it's ghost-like but it's also supposed
to be superior to all other opinions
so for example in marxist critique of
the bourgeoisie it's like
the bush i think they're superior to the
rest of the people they think they're
better
or in our case today our problem is not
racism or sexism our problem is
generationism
our problem is the myth that we are
superior to previous generations that
have died
so therefore we could think higher of
ourselves because we're smarter than
they are or no better they do
and it's ridiculous it's exact opposite
we're actually
caught in our own collective idiocy at
the moment but this
voice doesn't have a name except that
heidegger mentions it
he disregards it he hates it he finds it
inauthentic
he finds it problematic and fake and
false
and he just calls it dazman but it
doesn't have a proper name
anywhere where i look and this is why i
took the word subject and i took the
word object and i took the word
object and then i thought anonymous is i
know
in in latin so that would be an object
it's like an
anonymous ghost that we assume leaders
but we also blame everything all we held
accountable
[Music]
interesting yeah because the gerard
victim
is um he's he's innocent and he's
arbitrary like he could be could be
anybody so that he said he's an object
that goes along with
with the the anonymous person no no no
it's the opposite that's the abject
andrew that is the object that's
objection theory that i think i would
blame everything on
no this is the exact opposite this is
where we take the blame from
this is the voice of the accuser
but it's always an anonymous voice
because one it doesn't exist
two it's only being assumed three we're
hiding behind it
and four if we're held accountable for
anything we do we blame it on somebody
else
so in christian theology this would be
like blaming the jews for
killing christ when reality all humanity
killed
christ the whole point was that even his
even his followers deserted him
yeah nobody stood behind you the point
with that story is to tell us that no we
all scapegoated him we all turn him into
the ability
that's exactly why anti-semitism in the
sense that it's the jews killed
our our messiah is the absolute lie this
ridiculous lie
that's always really ironic yeah yeah
and it's an anojector this is an analogy
the anarchic is of course the good
christian who blames the evil jew
you see how the anoject is necessary to
to to come
to to fill the entire jigsaw the entire
apostle
and that opens up a whole new space for
understanding the messiah figure
and for understanding the difference
between the messiah figure and the
tyrant
it is what i've been lacking i've been
looking for years
because we all know from zoroastrianism
that the phallus has to be split
we know the egyptians experimented with
uniting
the phallus this is not and this led to
atonism this is the origin
of the jewish religion and that's
perfectly fine that's what you do with
something where you go through something
and that's how the jews invented a
system where they avoid
dictatorship within the religion whereas
egyptians went for the dictatorship the
egyptians invented the dictatorship of
mimicking the persons and getting it all
wrong
and that's why they invented the sun god
as the only god
but the problem is that monotheism has
to be split at the center
the phallus has to be split the
chieftain and the priest must never be
the same person
this is what the persians understood and
this was sore astronomism
provided us with a religion that held
the persian empire together for 1400
years
uniquely in history we're going to do
empire theory today we have to start
with the persons we have to go to the
persons
so but the thing is that if you split
the phallus the trick is then
when this ocean derives it's a rasterian
mythology
when the messiah arrives in judaism when
the savior arrives in christianity
when the mod arrives from islam the
crystals or the
yeah he always has the character of the
tyrant because he unifies the chieftain
and the priesthood into the same person
now what i did then was that i started
to thinking in a white hedian manner
about this
and in whitehead the only thing that's
interesting is the relation
that was why zoroaster and whitehead
work so perfectly well together because
erastus says
the phallus is split and in hegelian
white tedion manner that means
that is the only phallus possible
because the phallus must be a relation
so sexually that is false inside matrix
that's a fuck
but if you lead if you if you take on
the phallic leadership the masculine
leadership if you lead if you're the
patriarch
the patriarchy has to be split between
the chief
and the priest fundamentally possible to
the match art
and by splitting the phallus we can lead
because we separate body from mind
so we have an expert in mind the priest
we have an expert of body who's the
chieftain
now if so has figured that out so rasta
vistaspa realized that because there
were two
they are really the uber match
nietzsche's mistake is to make the uber
munch into an individual
when a reality the uberman should be in
a white headed manner split
to become image ubermensch should be a
relationship
because everything is relations hegel
and white are adamant about this
everything is about relations
it's radical relationalism so the
associate
must then see the source to figure this
out be a relation
and that's why persons are some
comfortable muslims and christians and
jews
come to the suras and said yeah you
meant to the savior you invented the
messiah we
got the idea from you we are new for
that and they go no you misinterpreted
it
because you took the egyptian version of
it you killed the rain god to keep the
sound good only whereas we always said
you must keep the rain god and the sun
god together
because it is the relationship between
the rain god and the sun god
that is god
[Music]
okay now that's interesting because
the jews have this idea about the you
know the god having uh a dark side and
the light side as well not just
there's like a dark god and a light god
as well oh yeah yeah yeah yeah it's a
bit similar to
oh there's so many of these i think once
you start splitting you should keep
splitting you should be spinosis to say
the universe is one
everything else is an infinite amount of
attributes you're allowed to split as
much as you like
and the way we men look at it is by
learning that the chieftain
and the priest must be separate we learn
that we are separate we learn that with
different types of men
we learn to admire other men for having
strengths that we don't have that is the
beginning of collaboration
that's exactly why competition can only
come out of an individualist mindset
that's completely misunderstood what it
means to be human
and be masculine because everything is
about relations now
but what's interesting here is that i
want to avoid making the associate into
the tyrant
because for me the tyrant is the false
phallus
who only appears in history where we
have lynch mobs like today
and somebody steps up and says we have
an abject here to hate that we unify
together with and this character must be
different from the session
or the messiah who's the savior because
otherwise adolf hitler would have been a
savior
obviously he wasn't we call this
authentic follow some fake
and fake phallus in this liberal but i
want to explore deeper
and rather than asking where the cell
shunt comes from the ocean
is the optimal relationship
between a king and a priest where
they're gonna save an empire
that's exactly what zoroaster means it's
optimal leadership
optimum mind and optimal body
collaborating
be responsible before a supreme court of
a matriarchy
to run an empire successfully so the
question is where does the tyrant come
from
and this is the trick the tyrant is the
anoject
personified so while we're
all in the lynch mode when we when we're
we're in the live spot we're comfortable
being there because we will never be in
the public arena nobody will ever put
our name out there no one ever
put our face out there we can hide
anonymously within the lens mob
and we're safe and comfortable and we
can love to hate which is exactly
what today's social justice warriors are
doing with our society
it's exactly what the lynch mobs are
doing at the moment and they're
basically preparing for the next hitler
or the next on and that's exactly what
they're doing
but whoever steps out of the social
justice warrior lynch mob
and suddenly personifies the energet
it's going to be deterrent in no time at
all
so it is in heidegger ironically the
nazi heidegger we
find how we gonna immunize ourselves
against the next hitler isn't that
ironic because heidegger red hitler
wrong
he saw a post-christian saber in hitler
when of course
you knew if you read minecraft in 1921
that was like the worst projection ever
this guy was clearly a guy who was ready
to take on
the the the shape of the energetic
personify the energetic and step into
the arena
and give the hate speeches and unify the
german people
the structures folk well it's kind of
it's kind of baffling that heidegger
made that mistake right so
there must be something in his
philosophy that that made him blind to
that
that's a very interesting question this
is where you guys come in because i want
to dress tonight i want to address the
difference between heidegger and
whitehead
they live simultaneously why ted is the
british guy who goes south to america
and he goes to harwood and
he stays away from europe and europe
goes to work whereas heidegger stays in
germany
and he placed around with the nazi party
he even sacrificed his own jewish
students including
hannah arndt in that process and
eventually of course the nazi party
turns against him too because they can't
use him much in the 1930s
but but it's interesting that that this
idea of the anarchic
is so close to whitehead and it comes
out of heidegger
and it just it didn't have a word what
i'm doing is that i'm in a freudian
sense giving it a word and calling it
the anaject
i can call the whole process and
objectification
so when we look at the lens mobs today
we can study them from the perspective
of an
objection an ejection study or an
objectification study give me a give me
a clear definition of the energetic
because i'm not quite there yet
okay because yeah exactly because we
speak we speak germanic languages that's
what's hard
in english and french to understand the
concept so what it is is that
when i don't want to speak with my own
eye and take responsibility for what i
say when i say
i believe and i think
i take responsibility for what i say to
the soros just you
must speak this way you're not allowed
to speak in an anonymous way
you must take responsibility for what
you say
it's called it's an ethical principle
for us to be interesting
the jews have the same principle you
must not speak in an anonymous
manner when you speak to other people
you must speak in a way that you take
responsibility for what you say
any mature religion that's fostered to
be grown up to do that
but in germanic languages you can hide
it's extreme actually in judaism they
say that gossip is a form of murder
right
um yeah elks and gossip anyway
this kind of gossip was what you
intrigued was what you're talking about
now
intrigue making like you keep this
within closed door and this is not in a
barred absolute sense you keep you don't
keep it within closed doors
because people aren't ready to hear it
you keep it in closed doors to to defend
your own interests without taking any
risks
and that's exactly what we're seeing
today what while the lynch mobs today
have the character of feminine hysteria
is because they refuse to look at
history and they refuse to look at the
future
and they're obsessed with an emotional
now
that's why feminine and hysterical
because the family is strong in the
presence when we do mindfulness we go
into the feminine we do anything but
focus on the now we do feminine
that's what women do well it's the
priest who's responsible for history
and it's the chieftain who's responsible
for the future as a man look
back into the history to learn that's
what priests do it's called gathering
intelligence
the wealthy intelligence when you look
into the future you want to transcend
you want to create a better world that's
called will to transcendence this is
what personified by the chieftain so
chieftain is the father of the future
and the priest is the father of the past
so you remove those two you castrate
them or you kill them
we don't have any priests around in our
society any longer do we no we don't
the castrated the professor says they
don't take that responsibility at all
nobody takes on the priesthood any
longer and the politicians are
completely corrupt and children cannot
take on any leadership in terms of
chiefness
we do not have any chieftains or any
priests out there that's exactly what
shlavashi
and i say in highly amanda that we moved
into the age of the feminine hysteria
there are no men around phallus is gone
both the phallus of history and the
phallus of the future
that's a really really really
apocalyptic scary stage to be in
that's a wrap right now and that's when
the lynch mobs come forward
and within the lens mouth because nobody
takes responsibility personal
responsibility for anything
nobody wants to be the sovereign
they just want to hide in the group and
then throw their it's like monty python
you know when the women dress up as men
to stone somebody to death
that that is women it is women dressed
up as men to kill somebody it's such a
prophetic scene
in in the monty python life lava bryant
movie
but it's exactly what is happening at
the moment so the women pretend
that they're powerful men or something
but they actually just go into the
feminine hysterical
they create these lunch mobs and they go
out and they throw rocks and they want
to hide
and the anodic is the voice that they
both
assume is speaking through them
but it's an anonymous voice so that if
they get blamed for what they do they
could just oh it wasn't me
that's why they say things like uh one
thinks
one believes or maybe hide behind a sort
of soft we
when we i noticed also that in in
discourse
you use a lot of we and not you like you
can't use
you can't you can't say you and you
can't say i you know in uh
well you can but then you have to take
responsibility
people don't say you because it's too
accusatory it's too direct and people
don't say i
because they don't take responsibility
so they they you kind of hide in this
in this collective weed it's what you're
talking about so when you
when you throw the rock of the lynch but
when you attack you say we
yeah you say we as we are right because
we are many and we are we
and you're alone and therefore you're
wrong and therefore that you can be
allowed to kill you
this is why i think that thomas has been
on to the scapegoat being just anybody
you pick
but the scapegoat must be alone so you
can gladly kill the scapegoat by being
the wii
and the escape companies the you that
you kill but as soon as you in
any way risk being held responsible for
throwing that rock or threatening to
throw it
you're moving to the well one thinks
that way one must believe that way
that that is the right thing to do i
mean a look around
in our society that this is the value
one must think this way
must think that way mama speak that way
this is what all these people do
and they're hiding behind academia today
in america like sadie is like
they're hiding by the academic world the
college has been taking over
the universe be taken over but this
crowd and the hiding behind and they
are superior simply because they are
they these people
but they're superior not because they
think better they're just they're just
superior
by chance by nature unconditionally
and when they say something they will
always say
that is and if it's a given well it is
also
the superiority that they they present
themselves as being
they always tag that to their um
sovereignty i mean their their
connection to people who are you know
lower than them or or worse
you know it's always middle-class people
who attack working-class people that's
what it's constantly that's why marx is
so useful
there's a whole new left now happening
in sweden they're leaving the social
democrats and
speaking about workers and going back to
marxist knowledge and they're wonderful
it's already happening mike anoxi
terrain marcus allard
malcolm kuhn is being published on north
america he's coming out of sweden this
black guy
they're amazing there are new left what
i've been looking for new marxist left i
could be a neat shit right i don't mind
that
the new marxist left and they're all
expressing the working-class
anger against the middle class that is a
lynch mob
[Music]
it's the middle-class people's way of
neglecting their own shortcomings and
replacing them with this attitude of
superiority and of course then they hate
the working class because that's where
they come from
and they picked up these middle class
values these bourgeois values it's
called marx said
and they do everything they can to feel
superior because they don't have the
arguments
they don't work hard like the
working-class people do they can't
maintain their marriages
they fail in every account where the
working class still functions
that's why they instead go for a battle
morality and hide behind lynch mobs and
political correctness
and they always then reproduce this
anoject at the center of it
yeah well gerard would say that
probably that the bourgeois also becomes
another scapegoat it's like
and the modernity like marx makes uh
the bourgeois scapegoat and um no i
don't
freud makes the father why would you why
would gerard say when did
when did gerard defend the middle
classes ever
when did he defend the middle class no
he what he said is he wants to reject
the the three scapegoats of modernity
and he says marx freud and um
and uh what was the third was the third
one
nietzsche anita right he wants to reject
the the you know nietzsche
would make the you know the christian
the scapegoat and then
um oh i think he's dead wrong marks
would make the bourgeois escape
anyway those three people yeah i think
gerard is dead wrong on that nature does
not
read christ as something he wants to get
over or he's attacking the christian
that's not at all what he does when when
he's regretting that god is dead and we
killed him
he means it in a very serious way this
is where jordan peterson gets it right
and if gerard is wrong on that then he's
wrong now
the christian is not turning to
scapegoat by anybody i haven't seen that
at all i don't think christianity
christianity does like thomas has said
before christianity
always defends us he he he wants
christianity is the priest who wants us
to get out of the scapegoating
so okay in a sore estrogen way
explaining christianity
this is how we describe it if the cell
is split that's wonderful because then
we can be saved at two different
instances the first is the chieftain
savior
he's the one who arrives us and fights
fights down the tyrant and the lynch mob
and saves us in the military manner
okay that's the messiah but there's
another messiah in case
the first messiah does not appear the
second messiah comes along and placed
the scapegoat
and then the priest can forever remind
us afterwards
that this is what happens if you kill
the messiah
so we can avoid tyranny and avoid
scapegoating
you see what i mean you're being more
sympathetic to christianity than usual
this time yes because no i think
thomas has been at me a lot about it
yeah and and
the point is that i had to go back and
say but the beauty of zoroastrianism is
destruction
but since the sorasus are frustrated
with the vulgarization of the social
concept
why don't we take the social concept
seriously and maybe
that's what the christians really tried
to do
and in that case they saw sean here the
savior
who was on the cross is the savior who's
there for the priests
who then you know do not have children
and go into
a complete devotion to preaching the
message of what happens if you have a
scapegoat
let's avoid that ever happening again
but
if the first messiah succeeds which of
course christ wasn't
the first messiah is the ultimate hero
fights down the dragon and kills the
dragon
and the dragon in that case is turning
it is the an object it is the tyrant and
his lunch model
and in that sense what we tried at least
to portray the amer
that america did in europe when they
fought down hitler um
and eventually we got rid of stalinism
we're still fighting maoism when we were
fighting these incidents we fighted
these dictatorships i'm personally
involved in trying to fight
the chinese dictatorship at the moment
by working with taiwanese hackers
it's one of my favorite preoccupations
now that is
of course hero fighting dragon but when
hero fights dragon in messianic sense
that is the first messiah
but to the persians both could exist
well that's very interesting yeah it's
either jesus would be the second messiah
yes in that theory yeah that's a sort of
a wild theory
yeah yeah the the problem is that so
so with respect to this uh so the
significance of jesus right so the
atonement so basically why
why why did did god send jesus to the
earth right
and um so so there there are there are
three
uh there are three views on that right
and the first one is well
god sent jesus to the to the to to the
world so that he could die for our sins
that's the one in my opinion that makes
the least sense
yeah and then there's the second one and
that is
uh well jesus is a moral example so an
example to follow now that's more
valuable i think but it's still a bit
problematic because i mean jesus ended
up on the cross right i mean
so this is kind of difficult to use also
there's some some
censored parts of jesus life that you
know that come out in these weird texts
where he does all kinds of wild things
like kill somebody when he was young
anyway that's just uh yeah so
but yeah but that um maybe unfortunately
did not survive in the
in the bible we have now right so um and
then there's
but then there's the third uh the third
explanation and this is the christus
victor explanation where basically
um that uh jesus is did not die for our
sins or
and and he's not a moral example to
follow as such but he reveals
the the the the victimized mechanism so
the mechanism of speech of scapegoating
itself
so and and that's basically uh so if you
look at christianity from that sentence
and basically christianity is the
is the ultimate anti-mob religion yeah
because the whole point
about christianity done well right
because of course there are many many
interpretations and you can twist this
any way you want right but but the value
in christianity lies in
look at what happened to jesus i mean
the jews didn't even kill him
and kill jesus themselves right they had
to ask their their sworn enemies the
romans to do it for them
so it's really the story of a human
being that was completely dehumanized
and killed and found guilty by everybody
and that christianity says that
the devil essentially that mechanism is
the devil so what we're seeing right now
for
for from that christian point of view
right what you're actually seeing out
there
all these mobs that's the manifestation
of the devil and the devil is not so
something you know some
uh some entity out there it's basically
a mechanism that humans do and they do
that if they don't have
a a religion that keeps them from doing
that well could you say that an object
is the devil or like the satanic
principle or something something like
that so the an object would be the the
the justification of the mechanism it
would be a story that is told to to
justify the whole thing
yeah because because because you you
legitimate something with history so
priests legitimate anything and
and the chieftain justifies it by
looking into the future legitimation is
what you do with history
justification we do in the future so the
energetic takes on these roles he steals
every role that any priesthood chieftain
could do and then becomes the time of
pretending to be both
i completely agree with thomas on this
strongly
there's no point in reading christianity
any other way you read the gospels it's
all
there there's no room for these first
two interpretations they made up
afterwards in a sort of bourgeois way
making christ in some kind of role model
think you could mimic
no never does christ usually mimic me no
he does not say that anywhere so you're
coming around i think to to seeing
christ as a crazy wisdom
no no no no i'm not that's because no
i'm not i'm
rather no i'm look take christianity
seriously
read your art seriously read the gospel
and believe me i've done that no it it's
a trinity that exposes it all there's no
room for the trinity in the first
interpretation of why christ was around
there's no room for him as the moral
example at all
but that moral example is like that's
like you know a traditional chinese
indian guru walking around you try to
mimicking
well that's only sutra anyways it
doesn't get you that far so that's a
banal religion worst case religion right
no it is the third one we need to go to
christ on the cross
to christians everywhere is the event
christianity is an evantology the
concept of the eventuality was invented
by zoroaster it's the only
major religious innovation ever
outside of eventology we only have
nominology we only have the eternal
recurrence of the same we only get mad
turkey wins at the end of the day
you know we only have everything goes
around round without ever
ever anything changing evan told this
idea
that something profound can happen in
history to change history forever
it's zoroaster's fundamental
contribution and it's the only real
radical break that's what it seems like
it moves from zoroaster to to judaism
yeah logical the ethnological
eventology is it's definitely goes west
eventology is zoroastrianism
so racism stays in dollar with taoism
buddhism which is the known mythological
part of it so astonish so
i always thought religion should be both
i'm more surprised than ever
but the eventology was then cleansed
from nominology and which should have
been a priestly religion
in egypt was developed into a mass
religion the probably always having
monotheism as a master that didn't is it
doesn't gel with people because people
are polytheistic fundamentally
politicism is religion bottom up
monotheism monotheistic misreligion top
down so monotheism in the egyptian sense
which is pure dictatorship
so they took modernism and everything is
united and affects everything else to be
that everything is one thing
when reality like spinoza said no that's
a complete mistake
monism is just the unity of everything
that everything affects everything else
but actually the world is split into an
immense multiplicity of things
that has an infinite amount of
attributes this would take spin also
seriously
now soreaster is the original spinosis
so this is true this is a trainer
thought all the way for zoroastrospinosa
but spinoza lacks or rasters pathos
and that's what you see them popping up
that could be used in christianity in
islam and certainly in judaism
and they deal with the pathos of the
logos of the mythos and the jews
solve it by taking the story of moses
an egyptian and leading an egyptian sect
out of that's when they were the jews
and became the hebrews
when they came to the promised land and
started mixing with the canaanites
and eventually three different gods
actually were turned into one
adonai in hebrew is atom
in egypt it's the same god you know it's
like freud said it's obviously that
atonists became the adonai worshipers so
that's what i have noticed the holy name
of all names for god in the jewish bible
so but adonai then
they added the volcano god which is of
course the rain god they needed to
re-add
rain god that was slacking it took a
volcano god because the other day it
says smaller dear weather doesn't matter
but when the earth shakes and you you
you're under the powers of nature
you need a volcano jave which then
became judea
and then they took elohim which is the
name for israel that became the kingdom
of israel
so elohim was the worship of one god and
and the worship of java was judea and
they were united through adonai
and they were later merged into a
trinity
this is the jewish trinity
in zoroastrianism it was simply it is
the priest
and the chieftain and the matriarch
so when the jews then wanted to
reinterpret the human story which is the
exodus alleged they couldn't use three
gods that led the people out of egypt
they took three siblings and they gave
moses
the egyptian prince a sibling called
aaron and aaron and moses changed the
roles of chieftain and a priest in
between but there were
always two that means the jewish
pharisees always split between the two
brothers
and and then they added miriam the older
sister who is the matriarch pushing the
entire people before her for 40 years
into the promised land and then moses
dies before they enter the promised land
as the priests you do
the chieftain leads the people into the
promised land and this becomes the
mythology the exodus
and to any jew you talk to it's
absolutely central there are three
siblings to the story
this so you're relating the three
siblings to or this
is in trinity okay the original exodus
out of age according to freud
was only moses and then he mistook it
for their two different moses
no there's moses aaron and miriam in the
later story and that story came out of
babylon with persian influence
so what the jews basically did they were
an egyptian sect monotheistic sect that
the persians
loved because the persians practiced
their own form of monotheism with the
split phallus
so you said that's brilliant by
separating mind and body into two
different forces within the same
divinity
we can create a trinity that's moses
sarah and miriam
so they could then have adonai elohim
and yava play the same role within the
god of judaism
now this is what then is really the holy
spirit is feminine
and exactly okay so it so if you're
moving to
in to move to the bard absolute with the
priesthood is in christianity
it is father son and spirit when you
take that into popular religion
and it's practiced it's of course father
son another
yeah that's what the catholics god well
i know in judaism the holy spirit
is actually feminine so yes yes they
changed it to masculine and christianity
so that yeah
also and this is on to what you're let's
leave islam out of it because they have
their own
comical versions of it but at least with
zoroastrianism judaism and christianity
we can now see a train of thought that
makes sense where there's a unity
between these three hematological
religions
and in this as we can go back and say if
christ wasn't the last savior
he was at least hopefully the last saver
to be the scapegoat and hopefully we
learned the lesson
and if you learned that as we're ready
for the next savior who might come in
and save us completely from day one
by killing the tyrant to the lynch mob
directly
so so there's there's an interesting
link to um
to between christianity and these mobs
right because
basically these mobs that's ancient
religion right it's basically paganism
it's kind of reverting back to the
the most primitive form of religion
that's let's find something to hate
let's unite and let's kill it and that's
basically what what is often uh
that's basically the idea behind that
that you could say like that's the
that's the that's paganism itself right
but the funny thing
is that that these mobs they have kind
of they have kind of inherited the
obsession of christianity with
protecting the victim which is a very
christian thing
um and and they use did they use that
concern so the typical christian concern
they use that to actually create a
a pagan religion or going through pagan
religious
emotions so that that's a very ironic
situation but that's what happens when
you remove christ
so if you remove the savior that's you
get the worship
of the victim and the the worship of the
victim is not christian
it's the corruption of christianity
before the in the roman empire right so
for example
the roman empire was a very civilized
empire right they were absolutely
unconcerned with protecting victims you
were
if you were a victim that meant that you
were just punished by the gods right so
so these types of mobs they would still
have mobs but they would use other
mechanisms to to to work themselves up
about oh yeah they're all pagan
you know they're pagan for one simple
reason they're unforgiving
they do not tell you there's a cell they
they don't give you a personal sentence
that says you've got to be punished for
this for the next 10 years then you're
free
no it's forever you must be killed it's
there it's final domination basically
yeah fatalistic yeah it's eternal
domination that is pagan that's exactly
where pagan and christianity differs
because in christianity it writes
forgiveness yeah so actually
internal damnation uh is is an idea that
that august late i read that late
augustine
he kind of promoted eternal damnation
but the orthodox christians they don't
believe in that they don't believe in
eternal damnation and actually paul
never said anything about
eternal damnation and that's a that's a
later um
it's magnificent pagan is it meganism uh
uh
pagan isn't entering christianity no it
is veganism entered christianity
it's not it's gnostic it's not pagan
it's not state
it's many kids manicurism has no
forgiveness either manicurism is just
the body's
evil the spirit is beautiful and
anything dealing with the body
is therefore evil forever but manicurism
has of course like all of them have
pagan roots but medicine never deals
with that
because manicurism never deals with
how you're going to solve the scapegoat
problem because it's it's enthralled in
the scapegoating process many cases
spread like
wildfire in the third and the fourth
century it was the widest most spread
religion in the world
fighting zoroastrianism and christianity
on two different fronts because it has
kind of a simplistic knowledge it was
excellent which which is very you know
attracted to the masses on some level
yeah
it is gnosticism and paganism combined
and this is my problem all the time with
augustine
i think augustine's confessions and i
think resource confessions are the two
worst books ever written in the west
i will constantly have problem with that
and i want to save christianity from
august and bring it back to paul
and see if we can solve this problem how
we match it in with zoroastrianism and
judaism
because i think that was the original
intention of christianity
well the intention of christianity is
very simple right don't do this pagan
stuff of making mobs and killing
uh killing these these uh these innocent
people all right
let's start using that making it it's an
inversion of the heroic myth right it's
like
it's a total inversion of the uric myth
being
kind of alone well the bible is a myth
told from the story of the person that's
that's who's the victim who's the
normally the perpetrators who write the
book
yeah so so christian yeah but where is
it
and that also has a negative possibility
that can be very corrupted as a
let's not be sloppy here okay if he's a
hero versus the victim
we don't have a problem with the victim
existing in the story as long as there's
a hero there
and as long as the victim doesn't go
after the hero
it's where the hero is gone the problems
occur
that's exactly what the lynch mobs today
are non-christian
that's why they hate martin luther king
they try to use him whenever they do but
actually he would hate them
because martin luther king was a proper
christian minister he told the blacks to
get their shit together
go to work love their children study
hard
and then have a career and if you work
as hard as the white people do even
harder you'll get more successful than
they are
that's why we beat racism that was
martin luther king's message in the
1960s and they
completely ignored today because they've
even removed him he's dead
so he's he's he's not as well it's true
they're trying to they they are trying
to
destroy the reputation of they'd hate
heroes because if you have heroes
then you cannot worship the victim they
want to worship the victim they are
personifying nietzsche's slave mentality
what the slave wants to do is to get the
master out of the way
so the slave can then worship the slave
and
beg for you know you know the perfect
example to become a banker
but this is again you're saying what
money is chris i want to magically get
them out of nowhere
christianity worships the victim doesn't
it i mean that's no
it doesn't really but but it it almost
looks like that so no
i'm saying what the dutch mob sort of
business that's going on right now is
like a corruption of christianity on
some level no no no that's rousseau
that is this is where souls break with
christianity remember that
when we get rousseau and we get the
worship of the tabula rasa we get the
worship of the innocent child who can
never do anything wrong
that is fundamental but that might be
i'm saying rousseau might be a
corruption of christianity no there's
nothing christian about rousseau andre
i'm adamant here
we are born sinners in christianity
we're not born victims we're born
sinners it's a fundamental difference
here
sin means that we're born short we're
not born fully mature
we're not born grown-ups we're not
certainly not one god we miss the murk
yeah so yeah so there is
there is so salvation there provided to
us
to work on ourselves to then improve on
ourselves and get ahead in life
and it's also along the time axis you do
certain things at certain ages
there are elders in the community
etcetera you look up to
this is not worship of victimhood
christianity would not have lasted for
two thousand years of a worship
victimhood
no but i don't know if you're getting
what i'm saying because i'm not saying
that
christianity is a worship of victim i'm
saying the corruption of christianity is
the worship of victimhood
and that that's like because because the
the lynch mobs
worship the victim right uh that's what
they do uh so
so and chris christ is the ultimate
victim
uh you know uh on some level uh you know
but that's a
you know but he's not really but but but
he is you know so
wait a second are you on christ's side
or in the lynch mob side here
if i'm a christian i'm on christmas i'm
definitely on christ's side
okay okay andrew then they're
they're not the same thing they're
opposites again that's what you asked
about the abject before and the anarchic
they think do with each other yeah
they're
opposites they're not the same thing at
all
so christ christ i didn't say the same
thing i say it's a corruption of it i'm
not saying they're the same thing
i'm saying that that's a corruption of
chris of christianity
yes says modern liberalism is sort of a
corruption of christianity right
capitalism is kind of a corruption of
protestantism uh you know
or or christianity you know no no
can we go back to the difference between
worshiping a hero and worshiping a
victim here
and stay there and stay focused on
master versus slave
okay fundamentally if you have an
ideology it will either worship a master
or you worship slaves
now if you worship the slave you want to
get the master out of the way
that means either the master is gone you
can run a mock in the streets that will
lynch mobs do
like they do at the moment okay they
don't want the masters to be there
they hate phallus more than anything
they go into the feminine hysteria
which is the the female world without
males present
and it's a world where you pretend that
the government will give you anything
magically when you ask for it
as if nobody had to pay taxes right
typical example of the current lunch
months
so magically you will get anything you
want at any given time
you are free of sin you're born innocent
but all-knowing yeah yeah i know i get
this this is the tabla rasa this is
rosso this is what the luna is supposed
to
now they don't last because you cannot
build the society on that foundation
it's impossible
for example today we are now surrounded
by prestige capitalism we're surrounded
by capitalism that pretends it's good
it wants to show its virtue signaling
and all that it's going to implode why
because it's a capitalism that tries to
ensure itself against risk-taking
when a reality capitalism is built on
fucking risk taking you cannot be an
entrepreneur unless you take risks
so it's going to kill business totally
and that's exactly what's going to
happen i'm going to go after prestige
capitalism in a fundamental way in the
2020s
because prestige capitalism is now
poison within capitalism
capitalism is nothing but making profits
and if you want to be good capitalist
you give the money back to the workers
and pay them properly
and then you give the rest to the
shareholders that's all the capitalists
are supposed to do
and then the workers can do whatever
they want with their money that they've
earned
that's good capitalism now capitalism
where you keep the money
pay your workers in a lousy manner but
pretend to avert the signal by giving
millions of dollars to black lives
matter
it's completely corrupted it it is a
capitalism that can
no longer be innovative and if it can no
longer be innovative and take risks it
will
die so the problem with all the lunch
problems is they always die
but unfortunately they get the tyrant
they have their 11 years of power and
they cause havoc and they kill
millions when they're there this is the
problem with the french revolution
this is probably the 11 years of adolf
hitler this is the probably most
cultural revolution
that's what i'm saying we're not going
to stay within this lynchpop anarchy
that we're stuck with at the moment but
it's going to get worse and worse and
worse until it gets better
and for a while it's going to get really
bloody that's
that's the history lesson we learned i'm
getting this from my vanilla
because evan ellich had this idea that
you know that that
um most the pathologies that you see in
modernity are
are corruption of of christianity on
some level and
i think there's something to that i
think they're pagan muslim
i don't think they're christian what do
you think thomas are you are you
following anything i'm saying or yeah no
i i i
agree with you uh andrew that that uh
that um
the lynch moves are often uh often
fueled by some kind of
corrupted form of of christian thinking
like again there's this typical concern
this this concern for the victim
is a typical christian thing so that has
survived in this pagan mob
and is being used to create the anoject
write the story of the an object and to
to
to target the hater towards a group of
people that can be hated right
so so but but so in another another
pagan
uh if if you you could use other
mechanisms to to create mobs right but
but often these these mobs they use some
kind of
some kind of moral system that is
derived from christianity
because the thing then okay corrupt way
i think that's what andrew tried to
point out
and i think that's also what gerard
basically uh like
like the roman empire for example they
they
there's there's they stopped because of
christianity they stopped child
infantile you know killing children or
something for for example like
there was all this like mercy but it was
still part of the roman empire
yeah but okay okay yes but again using
heidegger and carrying here
bersogen uh do you seriously think any
social justice warrior cares about the
victims that they
cherish as if they were heroes of course
oh no it's a pseudo-caring it's
a yeah it's exactly that that that is
excuse so we agree on that one yeah we
agree on that one yeah because it's an
excuse to make a mob basically i mean
the goal is to make the mob to be in the
mob
and to have something to to hate and to
unite you you unite around the hatred
right
so so that's that's the real goal of
what's going on
so the these concerns of these and it's
possession too it's fully
you know primitive possession of
ideological possession and pretty
i think i think today the lunch mobs are
are they're bitter and they're
narcissistic
and uh that means for good or bad that
means a lot of the guys in these
movements
want to step forward and personify the
energy yeah
and also i was thinking that they also
feed these these guys on on the
alt-right or whatever who
who want to you know create chaos so
that that you know the
mussolini comes riding in on a horse and
uh you know saves the day or
makes their trains run on time or oh
yeah
they copy each other right because
because what the excesses of the left
are then
are then compensated by excesses on the
right and they they kind of fuel each
other on right
yeah this is also something that gerard
has described so this this escalation
he has written a book about it actually
klozovich uh i believe so um which which
is basically about how countries also
when they get into conflict right that
they
they basically escalate uh by by just
copying each other's actions
oh yeah the alt-right grows from the
outlaw red cross that's why they love
each other the name for that is portland
oregon today
that is a place that has it's been going
on now for months and there's no end to
it
and portland oregon is probably the
place where the old left and the
alt-right in america are being
weaponized
at the moment which means the escalation
will continue and they will start
shooting each other
thaddeus russell then has the idea that
the national guard should relatively
have to step in and shoot them all
because of america's always done maybe
that will save america maybe the
constitution will say america
but the havoc will certainly be there
for years to come
the mess we see in america today is just
going to grow and grow there's no end to
it at all
because these guys haven't figured out
why these lunch pops are there in the
first place
and it's incredibly comfortable to join
a lunch mob when it's presented as a
facebook forum which is close to the
outside world
you can you can appear in an anonymous
manner
and suddenly anybody everybody can unify
around a certain voice the an object
here as soon as the antidesist within
the echo chamber
the next thing they do is that they find
something to hate wow it goes electric
oh yeah you want to go back and stay
within that form you want to stay in the
echo chamber when it has a clear
cut enemy you can attack and if donald
trump isn't the enemy any longer because
he can't play the role any longer
you've got to find an alt-right guy or
something like that that you attack
instead
and by unifying around this object the
anaject
starts speaking through the voice of the
echo chamber
that's what we're seeing in this forum
today and then
this is the problem as soon as there's a
sense
that there's a shared voice that
everybody's hiding behind like a ghost
benedict then anybody who takes on that
role and steps into that costume
becomes the tyrant it could be a man or
a woman doesn't matter but it's
if anybody steps into and personifies
that energetic
so for example when slavishing and the
guys to the left are saying that
there is a particular person who
personifies the universal
so this is very hegel so so what happens
is when you have a movement out there
saying intersectionality is that
the ultimate um transsexual
resentful lesbian gender change or
whatever you got that has as many skin
colors
and as many victim cards you could
possibly have to maximize the victim
cards
if that person only in a sentence
speaks the voice of the anarchic that
already exists if that person starts
personifying the object
boom and if that person gets killed
they've got their scapegoat then they've
got a movement and the lynch mobbing
can't go on and on forever
these mechanisms work in both directions
in that sense and that's where we're at
at the moment
now they tried to turn george floyd
afterwards into that character
that is vulgar christianity they tried
to turn george floyd into a scapegoat in
hindsight
and like he was an innocent child he was
killed by the brutal police or whatever
it doesn't matter what the actual case
was that's to be settled in court anyway
send the police guys whatever off
the person forever whatever you want to
do there's nothing to do with this but
the way they're using yours floyd in
america is by by making it a christian
scapegoat in hindsight
when a reality that's also done through
through through image an image you need
an image
right the image of the police boot on
his neck or something something like
that
that's that's what you need to to get
something like that going it's like
you need an image but he's not he's not
it's not a scale right because it's not
he's not seen as as he's actually seen
as as
somebody who's innocent who was killed
you know in a ghastly manner which which
was of course
exactly the case but that's the scandal
that is used to create this
the the the scale right yeah yeah the
scapegoat would be
you know like you see these police
officers kneeling and stuff like that so
it seems that the police is now
is getting a lot of is to a certain
extent put in this position so there
there's these very simple stories where
very black and white thinking
uh no pun intended but um so so where
you have like there's this this terrible
thing that happened and now we can use
we use this this this event to create
a to to create a unity in our community
by targeting a very specific
set of people who are seen as absolutely
guilty and that's the scapegoat right so
this these people need to be seen as
these people need to be completely
dehumanized for that to work
yeah and that's the scapegoat so the
scapegoat everybody agrees that the
scapegoat is
is completely guilty you know to think
of uh epstein weinstein these kind of
people
right absolutely guilty not not even no
there's a uni
you're not immediate to to to the
person's guilt which
yeah the scapegoat might might will be
guilty right i mean
i think that like concerts something
like even if your wife is cheating
if the husband is jealous it's still
pathological right so nobody's
saying that the escapes or escape goats
are necessarily completely innocent or
even part of the innocent
but they are turned into something that
is not they're not seen as humans
anymore
and this is something that christianity
very much warns about so in that sense
it's an it's a corrupted form of
christianity because christianity very
careful
about about attributing complete guilt
to people and then
painting them as inhuman because that
that's very dangerous
that's basically a pain that leads to
paganism basically
yeah okay well that's why these
characters and dostoyevsky novels are
you know are forgiven in the end or
something like they might have done all
these
really bad things but um but but but
they're they're always humanized
on some level um yeah did he
unite he was very good at painting
even people he he strongly disagreed
that he made them very human and
understandable
exactly yeah just i was thinking of this
whole host of
doskieskian characters which are sort of
that's a
very essential it's a very interesting
pattern here and i mean i need to work
more on it and certainly learn from you
guys about the scapegoat as i just
learned from thomas here respectfully
uh what i've been concentrating on is
the opposition between the anoject and
the object
and the object this is stream strictly
lynch mob technique so
the absolute somebody that unifies the
lynch mob
all the cowards of the villains who are
unified because they comfortably can
attack somebody
and within the lynch mob soon the
materializes the idea of a shared
voice shared opinion that the goal can
hide behind this
voice in an anonymous matter that's why
it's called the anoject
as soon as the anarchy exists it
provides an opportunity for somebody to
step in and take the role and just speak
as if he or she was the antiject him or
herself she's probably
probably somebody's very intuitive
narcissistic
sociopathic power grabbing and has
no nothing left for anybody else except
him herself
so it is certainly hitler character but
it certainly did several of these
characters in the social justice warrior
bob at the moment who could take on that
role
the anarchic steps forward takes on the
leadership and by simply speaking in a
way that is assumed
to be the proper say bourgeois middle
class attitude
towards the rest of the world that
becomes the antidepth and the anardic
will then
milk whatever victim they find out there
who they don't care for the victims that
are dead are perfect because the dead
victim making them milk
to continue their story so for example
hitler would have gone around after 1933
and any sort of aryan young man who had
been mistreated in any way whatsoever by
any jew at any time could have been used
as victim
in that sense to add to that story and
that's how the story escalates
now the scapegoating mechanism though is
different from that so that's where
gerard and christianity comes into the
picture that's when it gets a lot richer
and and um i guess i have to learn more
about it
how is the scapegoat different from the
object let's put it that way it's not
only a difference in perspective it's
the scapegoat is always an object but
not all objects are scapegoats
the scapegoat could be anybody i as far
as i understood
he he didn't he doesn't it's random who
the scapegoat
is it's absolutely random it's actually
he's guilty according to arbitrary
okay but he's skilled according to
everybody if i run a lynch mob
it's only my lynch mob to have to be
convinced that the guy we're going after
is an
abject yeah it's based on human
sacrifice think of it that way like
think of it in his most primitive sense
right the scapegoat is the cripple who
you know
you you would scapegoat him you would
sacrifice to him
to make the gods happy to end the war of
all against all
um you know to end the the natural the
aggression that would exist and
and and uh to it's just
this you know the human the human desire
for
for um for for you know uh for for blood
is appeased
oh yeah i i get i get it from gerard
that there's tension and the only way to
release the tension is to find a
scapegoat and that is the release
uh and but like thomas said this is
what's so important the scapegoat is
guilty according to everybody the escape
code is a homo saucer as george organ
says
he's completely dehumanized only then
can he be the scapegoat
so even if he's randomly picked doesn't
matter he has to be dehumanized at the
point here
i mean everybody's created is that the
entire public
so it's a religious it's a the thing of
the scapegoat it's a religious
ceremony right almost it's it's it's
very it's
it's the beginning of religion that's
that's gerard's theory
that the religion begins with that the
first altar that you build and then you
you know you put the scapegoat on them
and then and then that's how human
civilization develops that's
that's the radicality of of gerard's
idea well
the first again
the the the first altar was or the
stones that were covering the
the body of the person that was stoned
to death right
that's one of the images that gerard
uses so for and
most religions they basically try to to
channel
this uh these mob dynamics so that they
can be
released and experienced but they don't
destroy everybody
because if if this mechanism is not
controlled and then you get
a war of all against all and and
basically you have a big slaughterhouse
right so religion tries to
to channel this this victimish mechanism
so that it becomes
workable that's pagan religion and so so
that's
myth and then on christianity kind of
dismantles this and says like well this
is not the right way to bring people
together and and
so let's let's get away from this
victimized mechanism so they replace
myth
with gospel so this is why the bible is
not it's not a mythical text it's
it's a gospel text so that's sort of
funny enough why jordan peterson is
often a bit like
he actually has a very pagan uh
way of looking at the bible and
constantly interpreting us as
mythological stories right
while while this this very core there's
a realism right that that
is introduced is that kind of
with the gospels right because
everything is fantastical in in
mythology
and then suddenly suddenly you get this
like common criminal
you know crucified on a cross and it's
like
the event it's the introduction of
realism on some level
is that what jordan peterson says or no
no no that's what that's
that's i i'm i'm i'm i'm
yeah yeah paraphrasing gerard yeah
suddenly
you know you have these these nice
mythological texts and suddenly there's
this story of
of of somebody was actually killed as
the most common criminal right because
crucifixion was something that was used
abundantly
it was not not very it was not a special
uh
punishment the romans crucified uh
people all the time yeah
i'm still going back to the scapegoat
versus abject here um
well i think that the difference is that
so for the for the scapegoat right
that you need so so as far as i
understand from christeva so the object
is also something that you reject like
she gives this example of
this milk that had gone bad and then
when it touches her lips then she
recoils so this is the
the object something that is outside but
but the scapegoat needs to you need to
be interested
in coming together and kill the
scapegoat so like an
orgasmic explosion of violence so
there's something very attractive in the
scapegoat as well
so there might be a certain difference
there right so that
that the object of christeva and then
the
the the the scapegoat of uh of of girard
but they're very related yeah the thing
is that we read it through hitler and
stalin and mao and then we discovered
that
they used the jew they used the kulak
and they used the parent
uh as both scapegoats and objects so
they they unified
their crowd their party their movement
it was it wasn't a universal hatred
towards somebody it was just it's just
within the group
within the sort of civilized population
within the political party
and that was the world anyway that was
their echo chamber
and then they found an abject and by
killing going after and slowly killing
the subject
they uh would then maintain their power
and and they
maintain this enormous sense of
togetherness and loyalty towards the
group
that's exactly what these systems were
incredibly productive too
then of course they got mismanaged after
a while because they they completely
trusted a dictator to know where to go
and when hitler took tons of amphetamine
and started the war against the soviet
union
stalin hitler just killed each other
eventually in that process and killed
100 million people in the process which
is like
two lynch mobs go to war with each other
they don't have a universal scapegoat
they all dehumanize rather than they
take the different
uh scapegoats they've had they might
change the interchange change them
between each other exchange scapegoat
certainly the jews had a lot of problems
in stalin's russia
after hitler folded ironically and i'm
sure it wasn't easier
for ukrainian kulak to appear subtly in
germany he wasn't cherished when he
arrived there in 1946 probably hated do
because these were like trash material
this is like yeah these are trash people
they're destroyed anyway we might as
well hate them the way our enemy hated
them
so in that sense there's a similarity
between scapegoat and abject
that's interesting but it is it is
objection theory as the overall theory
is called it's all about
how you unify a population by finding
something that you
hate together and of course as a human
being you have to dehumanize it
to then allow yourself to hate it
without remorse
yeah and the other way of doing that
without the remorse it's not only that
it's okay according to the official
ideology to hate the jew because you're
a nazi
it's also that somebody else
speaks through the crowd so hitler is
ultimately responsible we need to
personify his time
but before hitler comes forward
there must have been a lunch mob
existing already where everybody
passively waiting for the tyrant to step
forward and take over
and that's not how saviors work the
savior works the opposite way
the savior comes in and kills the dragon
so the savior
fights political correctness the savior
fights against the status quo
the savior brings a whole new world a
whole new paradigm
a whole new emergence vector if you want
with him
and then forces the new world onto the
people and they're like they don't want
to accept it the same across the holy
world let's say he said
this is the new world and you better
adapt to it because i want to take you
there
and that's why the savior takes you into
where you're at
and brings a minority of people who say
yes to being saved
wear them into the exodus and they then
go
into the promised land which is another
world instead of staying
so they don't literally kill anybody
they just leave